campsystems.com 2016-04-12

# CAMP Systems International, Inc. Privacy Policy

Effective: March 14, 2016

We at CAMP Systems International, Inc. ("CAMP Systems" or "we" or "us") know that your privacy is important. This privacy policy is designed to assist you in understanding how we will collect and use the information you provide, either when you use CAMPSystems.com or our web applications mtx.campsystems.com and mtx30.campsystems.com (collectively "Website(s)"). Please read this privacy policy to learn more about the ways in which we collect and use your information. If we make any material changes to this privacy policy, we will notify you in accordance with the process described in the Changes section of this privacy policy. By using our Website(s), you consent to our collection, use, and disclosure of your information as described in this privacy policy. 

CAMP Systems International, Inc. complies with the U.S. – EU Safe Harbor Framework and U.S. - Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal data from European Union member countries and Switzerland. CAMP Systems International, Inc. has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement.  To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view CAMP Systems International, Inc.’s certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>.

This CAMP Systems International, Inc. privacy policy complies with the VeraSafe Website Privacy Program Certification Criteria. 

## 

Information We Collect 

### Information We Automatically Collect

When you access our Website(s) whether by computer, mobile phone or other device, we automatically collect certain information about your use of our Website(s) (this information may include without limitation: geographical location and IDs of your computer, mobile or other device; bandwidth used; system and connection performance; browser type and version, operating system; length of visit; page views; referral source; IP address or other unique identifier for your computer, mobile phone or other device; your mobile carrier) using technologies such as cookies and web beacons.

This information is not linked to personally identifiable information. 

### Information You Provide To Us

In some situations you may provide us with your personal identifying information (called “PII”). PII could include your name, email address, mailing address, phone number, fax number, job title/position, information about your company or business and any other information we collect about you that by itself is not PII but if combined with PII could be used to personally identify you. 

You may provide us with PII when you:    
subscribe to our Website services, email notifications and/or newsletters;  
register for certain services, or register and/or set up an account/profile to access, visit and/or use certain portions of our Website; and  
any other transactions between you and us.

## 

Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies 

A “cookie” is a small file stored on your hard drive that contains information about your computer. We may use cookies to enable us to track and target your interests for the purpose of enhancing your experience on our Website(s). By showing how and when visitors use the Website(s), cookies help us identify how many unique users visit us, save user preferences and track user trends and patterns. 

We use session cookies, which are cookies that are deleted when you leave our Website(s) and persistent cookies, which are cookies that remain after you leave our Website(s) so that you are recognized when you return.

The use of cookies is industry standard so your browser may be set to accept cookies. If you would prefer not to accept cookies, you can alter the configuration of your browser to reject all cookies or some cookies. Note, if you reject certain cookies, you may not be able to access all of our Website(s) features. 

### Web Beacons

We may use web beacons (also known as clear GIFs) to access cookies and count users who visit our Website(s) or open our HTML-formatted email messages. Web beacons are single-pixel graphic files with a unique identifier, similar to cookies. Web beacons are embedded invisibly on web pages and are stored on a user's hard drive. You can modify your browser settings to control web beacons. 

## 

How We Use Your Information 

### CAMP Systems Will Use Information We Automatically Collect To:

Improve your experience on our Website(s);  
count users who visit our Website(s) or open our HTML-formatted email messages;  
improve the delivery of our ads and/or web pages to you; and  
help us better manage content on our Website(s) by informing us what content is effective and by helping to measure traffic on our Website(s).   

We may use IP addresses to help diagnose problems with our server, administer our Website(s), analyze trends, track users' movement, gather broad demographic information for aggregate use in order for us to improve the Website(s), and deliver customized content. 

### CAMP Systems Will Use PII To: 

respond to your inquiries, and/or other requests or questions;   
enable your use of the services available on our Website;  
send you invoices;  
send you email notifications which you have specifically requested;  
send you email marketing communications relating to our business, which we think may be of interest to you; and  
send you email messages containing company news, product or service information. 

## 

Security

CAMP Systems has implemented and follows commercially reasonable measures to protect against unauthorized access to and unlawful interception or processing of PII. Unfortunately, data transmission over the Internet is never 100% secure so we cannot guarantee the security of any information you transmit to us or from our Website(s) therefore, you use our Website(s) at your own risk.

If you register on our Website(s) you are responsible for protecting the security of your user name and password. You are responsible for any transaction made using your user name and password.

## 

Third Party Websites

Our Website(s) may contain links to third party content or websites that CAMP Systems does not control. This includes links to clients, sponsors and partners. NOTE: if you click on these links and enter a third party’s website these third parties may use their own cookies to collect data or solicit PII. You should read the third party website’s privacy policy to learn how they will collect and use your information as their policies may differ from ours and will apply to your use of their website. 

CAMP Systems is not responsible for the treatment of your PII or any of your information by any third party.

## 

Changing or Updating Your Information 

You can access, change, delete or update personal information you have provided and your subscriptions or preferences regarding information you receive from us by logging into the application and making changes or you may write to us at the address found in the Contact Us section of this policy.  We will implement your requested changes as soon as we reasonably can. When you edit your information or change your preferences, information that you remove may remain in our databases or backup media because it is not always possible to completely remove or delete information from those locations. 

### Opting Out

You may opt-out of having your PII shared with third parties for reasons other than for the express purpose of providing our services to you and except as required by law. You may also request updates or changes to your information or your preferences regarding receiving future promotional messages from us. To do this you may contact our Privacy Officer using the information in the Contact Us section of this privacy policy.

Please note that if you opt-out of promotional/marketing emails, you may continue to receive certain communications from us, such as administrative and services announcements and/or messages about your account/profile. 

## 

Disclosure of Information / Sharing Your Information 

We may disclose your PII (a) to the extent required by law or if we have a good-faith belief that such disclosure is necessary in order to comply with official investigations or legal proceedings initiated by governmental and/or law enforcement officials, or private parties, including but not limited to: in response to subpoenas, search warrants, or court orders or (b) if we sell or transfer all or a portion of our company’s business interests, assets, or both, or in connection with a corporate merger, consolidation, restructuring, or other company change or (c) to our subsidiaries or affiliates only if necessary for business and operational purposes or (d) to our vendors if necessary in order to provide you with service as further described below.

Without your express consent, your information will not be sold, exchanged, transferred, or given to any other entity, other than those acting as our agent to perform task(s) on our behalf and under our instructions, for any reason that is not compatible with the reason that you originally shared the information (except as described herein). 

We may use third party vendors to perform certain services on our behalf, such as hosting our Websites, maintaining, enhancing, or adding to the functionality of our Websites, operating our Websites' features, assisting with promotions, tracking web analytics data, enabling us to send you email, or performing other administrative services. We may share your PII with these third party vendors solely to enable them to perform the services for us. In providing such information, we require that those third party vendors maintain at least the same level of confidentiality that we maintain for such information.  We do not provide your PII to parties unconnected with the services we provide. 

We reserve the right to use, transfer, sell, and share aggregated, anonymous data, which does not include any PII, about our Websites' users as a group for any legal business purpose, such as analyzing usage trends and seeking compatible advertisers, sponsors, clients and customers.

Except as provided in this privacy policy, we will not provide your information to third parties.

## 

Child Privacy 

Our Websites are not directed at, or intended for use by, children under the age of 13. We do not knowingly allow anyone under 18 to provide any personal information on our Websites. Children should always get permission from a parent or guardian before sending personal information over the Internet. If you believe your child may have provided us with personal information, you can contact our Privacy Officer using the information in the Contact Us section of this privacy policy and we will delete the information. 

## 

Changes to This Privacy Policy 

We may update this privacy policy from time to time by posting a new version on our Websites. You should visit this page occasionally to ensure you agree with any changes.  We will post our revised privacy policy on our Websites and update the "Effective" date above to reflect the date of the changes. 

By continuing to use our Website(s) after we post any such changes, you accept the privacy policy as modified.

## 

Questions or Concerns, Contact Us 

If you have a complaint, dispute or questions regarding this privacy policy or our treatment of your information, please write to our Privacy Officer by email at support@campsystems.com 

or by postal mail at:

Attn: Privacy Officer, CAMP Systems International, Inc.  
Kevin O’Shaughnessy  
999 Marconi Avenue  
Ronkonkoma, NY 11779

### Dispute Resolution for U.S. - EU Safe Harbor and U.S. - Swiss Safe Harbor Claims

If a complaint or dispute cannot be resolved through CAMP Systems' internal process, CAMP Systems has agreed to participate in the [VeraSafe EU Safe Harbor Dispute Resolution Procedure](http://www.verasafe.com/safe-harbor-dispute-procedure) for U.S.-EU and U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor disputes. To file a complaint with the procedure, please submit the required information to VeraSafe here: <https://www.verasafe.com/dispute-submission>

[Privacy verification powered by VeraSafe](http://www.verasafe.com/).
